AMBER MARKEY

Director of Engineering

SUMMARY

• amber.markey@gmail.com

(785) 727-8567

• LinkedIn: /ambermarkey

Versatile engineer with an impressive breadth of experience in a startup culture, leading and collaborating with a multi-disciplinary team to successfully launch several Bluetooth-enabled medical devices. Professional history includes project, supplier, and product management, and quality assurance, ensuring a complete approach to new product design and development.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Product Management, Strategy, and Prioritization
- Product development and lifecycle processes
- Experience leading development teams
- Medical Device design under FDA regulations
- Project Management
- 7 years experience working with injection molding suppliers in Korea, China, and USA
- 4 years of experience prototyping designs and utilizing quick-turn manufacturing methods (3D printing, Express surface mount services) to verify designs

SKILLS

- Solidworks Design, development of injection-molded components
- Altium Review of, and simple edits to, PCBA layout
- JIRA Change tracking and implementation planning
- Git Version control
- Python, R, SQL Intro level, self-taught; data analysis
- Microsoft Suite Pivot Charts, Powerpoint, daily use
- FDM and SLA 3D printing
- Amateur Arduino development
- Soldering; building simple electronics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Strive MedTech

March 2021 - Present

Green Bay, WI (Remote)

Director of Engineering

- Strategized with CEO on direction of hardware and software products
- Established scope and directed development of two new product lines
- Selected vendor; directed development, integration of manufacturing test system
- Assessed SW stack tech trade-offs and worked with engineering to prioritize work
- Served as Customer liaison for implementation new service lines; established project requirements, timelines
- Developed working knowledge of full-stack structures

GE Healthcare - ARC

July 2020 - March 2021

Madison, WI

Global Product Manager

- Directed end of life processes for three anesthesia product lines: Supply chain shutdown for spare parts; transition plans from legacy systems to new product offerings; global product catalog management
- Managed acquisition and integration of two compressor product lines with crossfunctional and international team

Propeller Health

September 2014 – July 2020

Madison, WI

Product Manager and Mechanical Design Engineer 2017 - 2020

- Responsible for hardware product roadmap
- Collaborated with the business dev team to make strategic product decisions
- Managed Product specs built on user research, requirements of customers and other external stakeholders, engineers, market direction, and new technologies
- Led daily stand-ups to prioritize and align engineering efforts on hardware dev
- Responsible for the development of eight new products, four that reached full scale production and four that were in NPI
- Design of formative and summative usability tests
- Experience working with patent/IP lawyers to generate and file new IP
- Collaborate within a small, tight-knit team of two other engineers to rapidly develop new accessory Bluetooth devices that attach to, and track use of inhalersd
- Develop and communicate design specifications for injection-molded parts;
 manage relationship with injection-molding suppliers; overseas travel

Supply Chain Manager 2016 - 2017

- Responsible for the evaluation and selection of a new Contract Manufacturing partner
- Audited multiple injection molding vendors and CMs
- Managed projects from NPI to full-scale production
- Led efforts to reduce COGS through alignment of BOMs for multiple products
- Managed the move from a small, single business unit CM to a tier 2 CM in the US
- Gained experience leveraging relationships with component manufacturers and vendors to reduce costs at the component level
- Developed test specifications in collaboration with embedded-system engineers
- Sought and received certification for internal auditing through BSI

Machinery Row Bicycles

March 2012 - September 2014

Madison, WI

Sales and Customer Service

Regularly achieved top sales associate

Epic Systems Inc.

ROA Test Engineer

2014 - 2016

August 2011 - March 2012

Madison, WI

Technical Services

- Worked with customer IT teams to trouble-shoot and fix software issues
- Self-initiated a software development project to improve end-user experience

Dr. Sarah Kieweg (KUME)

February 2009 - August 2011

Lawrence, KS

Student Lab Assistant, Graduate Research Assistant

- Attended and presented research on a novel microbicide delivery vehicle at International Microbicides Conference in Pittsburgh, PA (May 2010)
- Conducted squeezing experiments on various gels to compare and develop math models of squeezing flow

EDUCATION AND HONORS

University of Wisconsin

Scattered Semesters 2013 – 2019

Madison, WI

- Satisfy curiosities in Organic Chemistry, Genetics and Biochemistry
- 4.00/4.00 Cum. Overall GPA

University of Kansas

12 CR toward M.S in M.E.

August 2010 - May 2011

Lawrence, KS

- Fluid Mechanics and Finite Element Analysis Focus
- 3.95/4.00 Cum. Overall GPA

University of Kansas

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering: Graduated with Distinction

August 2006- May 2010

Lawrence, KS

- 3.93/4.00 Cum. Overall GPA; 4.00/4.00 Cum. Engineering GPA
- Tau Beta Pi: Engineering Honor Society--Initiated Fall 2008 as part of the top 1/8th of engineering graduating class
- Phi Kappa Phi: University Honor Society--Initiated Fall 2008 as part of the top 1/8th of graduating class
- Outstanding Service and Research Award (Spring 2010)
- Lindquist Memorial Scholarship (Spring 2009)
- Robert M. Carey Scholarship (Fall 2008-Spring 2010)
- KU Initiative for Maximizing Student Diversity: undergraduate research funding recipient (Fall 2009-Summer 2010)

INTERESTS

- Products that serve a greater purpose enabling people to live independently and sustainably within their own environment
- I thrive and am very interested in a fast-paced, start-up environment
- Learning to code in Python, Arduino IDE, and C++; building smart devices for personal use
- All things bikes (the pedal kind), ultra- trail running, hiking, cross country skiing